<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | ART</title>
    <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/img/thumbnail_bettis_churn.jpg</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ART Research presented at NURETH-20</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/nureth20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/nureth20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2023 ANS Annual Meeting in Indianapolis, IN, several members of ART presented their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Kang presented two summaries, entitled &amp;ldquo;Flow Regime Classification Using Orientation-Independent Layered Spectral Clustering&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;RGB Mapping: A Dynamic Approach for Flow Pattern Identification and Classification&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Dix presented a &amp;ldquo;One-Dimensional Drift Flux Analysis of Bubbly Flows in Horizontal and Inclined-Upward Orientations&amp;rdquo;, on behalf of co-authors ART alum Dr. Drew Ryan and Dr. Seungjin Kim&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Dix Wins First Place in the Nuclear Energy University Program&#39;s (NEUP) 2023 Innovations in Nuclear Energy Research and Development Student Competition</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-insc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-insc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Dix, a Ph.D. student and member of ART, has won first place in the Innovations in Nuclear Energy Research and Development Student Competiton with the journal publication &amp;ldquo;A Novel Friction Factor Model for Wire-Wrapped Rod Bundles&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this national competition, the Department of Energy’s (DOE) Office of Nuclear Engineering Nuclear Energy University Program (NEUP) recognizes and awards graduate and undergraduate students for innovative nuclear energy research publications. Adam Dix won first place in the Open Competition Nuclear Engineering category and was awarded a $3,500 and will have the opportunity to present his publication at the annual ANS Winter Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View all 2023 awardees 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neup.inl.gov/SitePages/Innovations%20in%20Nuclear%202023%20Winners.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ART Research presented at the 2023 ANS Annual Meeting</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/</guid>
      <description>




  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-from-left-to-right-david-kang-adam-dix-and-zhengting-quan&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/TRSL-2_hu966131f15c4a5b0e02ff23bb375f44b1_1156646_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;From Left to Right: David Kang, Adam Dix, and Zhengting Quan&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/TRSL-2_hu966131f15c4a5b0e02ff23bb375f44b1_1156646_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2840&#34; height=&#34;1956&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    From Left to Right: David Kang, Adam Dix, and Zhengting Quan
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the 2023 ANS Annual Meeting in Indianapolis, IN, several members of ART presented their research.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-phd-student-david-kang-presents-his-research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/David_presenting_ANSAM2023_hua7e5543fc428cd276bb7ff2284c94ab0_1861657_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ph.D. student David Kang presents his research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/David_presenting_ANSAM2023_hua7e5543fc428cd276bb7ff2284c94ab0_1861657_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;4624&#34; height=&#34;3468&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Ph.D. student David Kang presents his research
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Kang presented his summary, titled &amp;ldquo;A Direct Comparison of Flow Visualization and Machine Learning for Inclined Two-Phase Flow Regime Identification&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-phd-student-zhengting-quan-presents-his-research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/zhengting_presenting_ANSAM2023_hu746507baf34dc7ef273056d32dae301b_508384_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ph.D. student Zhengting Quan presents his research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-annual-2023/zhengting_presenting_ANSAM2023_hu746507baf34dc7ef273056d32dae301b_508384_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2325&#34; height=&#34;1689&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Ph.D. student Zhengting Quan presents his research
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zhengting Quan presented his research, titled &amp;ldquo;Numerical Investigations of the Single-Phase Flow Characteristics in U-Bends&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, ART alum Dr. Drew Ryan presented a paper titled &amp;ldquo;Improving Multiphase CFD Closure Models for Horizontal Bubbly Two-Phase Flow&amp;rdquo;, co-authored with Adam Dix and Dr. Seungjin Kim&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Dix receives Early-career Graduate Reserach Award and Graduate School Outstanding Service Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-service_early_career/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-service_early_career/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Dix, a graduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University and member of ART, has been awarded the Early-career Graduate Research Award from the School of Nuclear Engineering. One award is given annually to a Nuclear Engineering Student based on research accomplishments (such as peer-reviewed journal publications/presentations &amp;amp; awards) in the first two years (for M.S.) or three years (Ph.D.) of their degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam also recieved Outstanding Student Service Scholarship from the Graduate School. The scholarship is designed to recognize outstanding service to the graduate student community, the School of Nuclear Engineering, and the College of Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Dix inducted into Alpha Nu Sigma Honor Society</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-alphanusigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-alphanusigma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Dix (Back Row, Center right), a Ph.D. student at ART, has been inducted into Alpha Nu Sigma, the nuclear engineering honor society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha Nu Sigma was founded by the American Nuclear Society in 1979 and consists of more than 20 chapters throughout the United States. The organization seeks to recognize and reward outstanding students in Nuclear Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Adam for this great honor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Kang receives Rickover Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kang-rickover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kang-rickover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Kang, a Master&amp;rsquo;s student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University and a member of ART, has been awarded a Rickover Fellowship from the Naval Reactors Division of the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE). This opportunity is considered as one of the most prestigious fellowships in the nation, awarded to top students pursuing a Ph.D. degree in nuclear engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four-year fellowship is intended to provide education on the maintenance and development of science and engineering technology pertaining to naval nuclear propulsion and advancing fission energy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David is recieving his Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Nuclear Engineering from Purdue in May 2023. He will continue on in ART for his Ph.D, focusing on experiments and machine learning for two-phase flow applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ART Research presented at the 2022 ANS Winter Meeting</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ans-winter-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ans-winter-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2022 ANS Winter Meeting in Phoenix, AZ, several members of ART presented their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew Ryan presented research titled &amp;ldquo;Evaluation of Computational Fluid Dynamic Models for Bubbly Two-Phase Flows in Inclined Upward Orientations&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-masters-student-david-kang-presents-his-research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-winter-2022/David_ANS_hu6f73a5e49f342e9adb0e18a20c1717c0_169402_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Masters student David Kang presents his research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-winter-2022/David_ANS_hu6f73a5e49f342e9adb0e18a20c1717c0_169402_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1600&#34; height=&#34;1200&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Masters student David Kang presents his research
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Kang presented his research, titled &amp;ldquo;Flow Regime Identification for Inclined Two-Phase Flows using Machine Learning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-phd-student-adam-dix-presents-his-research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-winter-2022/Adam_ANS_hu8af7043b2beb3e35edd9a7670a6829e3_97183_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;PhD student Adam Dix presents his research&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/post/ans-winter-2022/Adam_ANS_hu8af7043b2beb3e35edd9a7670a6829e3_97183_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    PhD student Adam Dix presents his research
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Dix presented work related to his Masters&amp;rsquo; thesis, titled &amp;ldquo;Evaluation of Pressure Drop Models for 7-Pin Wire-Wrapped Rod Bundles&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Dix successfully defends Masters Thesis</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-master-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-master-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ART student Adam Dix has successfully defended his Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis titled &amp;ldquo;Experiments and Pressure Drop Modeling for 7-Pin Wire Wrapped Rod Bundles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam will be continuing his studies as a Ph.D. student at ART. Congratulations Adam!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drew Ryan successfully defends Ph.D. Dissertation</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ART student Drew Ryan has successfully defended his Ph.D. Dissertation titled &amp;ldquo;Experimental Analysis on the Effects of Inclination on Two-Phase Flows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew will be moving on to be an engineer at Bettis Atomic Power Laboratory. Congratulations Drew!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Seungjin Kim takes on leading role in the Purdue - Duke Energy nuclear power exploratory study</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-duke-purdue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-duke-purdue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Seungjin Kim, the Capt. James F. McCarthy Jr. and Cheryl E. McCarthy Head and Professor of Nuclear Engineering and Director of ART, has been named a Principal in Charge of the Purdue University - Duke Energy nuclear power exploratory study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2022/Q2/purdue-and-duke-energy-to-explore-potential-for-clean,-nuclear-power-source-for-campus.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;April 2022&lt;/a&gt;, Purdue University and Duke Energy announced their plan to jointly explore the feasability of using advanced small modular nuclear reactors for the energy needs of the Purdue West Lafayette Campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with Dr. Seungjin Kim, two other Principals in Charge were named to ensure the success of the exploratory study: Michael B. Cline, the senior vice-president of Purdue administrative operations and Chris Nolan, the vice president of new nuclear generation of Duke Energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the exploration new nuclear energy sources for Purdue University 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2022/Q2/purdue-and-duke-energy-advance-nuclear-power-exploration-with-public-lecture-series,-executive-advisory-group.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhengting Quan inducted into Alpha Nu Sigma Honor Society</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/quan-alphanusigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/quan-alphanusigma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zhengting Quan (Front Row, Far Left), a Ph.D. student in ART, has been inducted into Alpha Nu Sigma, the nuclear engineering honor society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha Nu Sigma was founded by the American Nuclear Society in 1979 and consists of more than 20 chapters throughout the United States. The organization seeks to recognize and reward outstanding students in Nuclear Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Zhengting for this great honor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drew Ryan receives Graduate Service Scholarships</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-service-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-service-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drew Ryan, a graduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University, has been awarded Graduate Student Service Scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew is the recipient of an Exelon Graduate Service Scholarship from the School of Nuclear Engineering, and a Graduate Service Scholarship from the College of Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scholarships recognize outstanding service to the graduate student community, the School of Nuclear Engineering, and the College of Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ART Students Win at NURETH-19</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/trsl-nureth-best-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/trsl-nureth-best-movie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drew Ryan, doctoral candidate at the School of Nuclear Engineering (NE), won the Best Movie Award at the 19th International Topical Meeting on Nuclear Reactor Thermal Hydraulics (NURETH 19). The conference took place virtually this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Held every two years in various destinations across North America, Europe and Asia, the meeting is one of the premier gatherings for experts in nuclear reactor thermal hydraulics and related fields&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan, along with his co-authors, received the Best Movie Award for his movie titled, “Inclined Two-Phase Flow Experiments.” The award is a welcome accolade for their recent research investigating how flow orientation effects two-phase systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View the movie 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EHMZC11Be7Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Kang selected for NRC Graduate Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kang-nrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kang-nrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Kang, an undergraduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University, has been awarded a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) Fellowship for continued studies at Purdue University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David will be receiving his bachelors in Nuclear Engineering from Purdue University May 2021. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s so nice to be honored with this graduate fellowship, and I look forward to studying for my Masters&amp;rsquo; Degree in Nuclear Engineering&amp;rdquo;. David will be studying the applications of global two-phase flow instrumentation and objective flow regime identification using neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drew Ryan receives Graduate Service Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drew Ryan, an graduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University, has been awarded a Graduate Student Service Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scholarship is designed to recognize outstanding service to the graduate student community, the School of Nuclear Engineering, and the College of Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ran Kong Featured on the Purdue Engineering Podcast</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kong_podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kong_podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ran Kong, ART Alum and Postdoctoral Researcher, is featured in an episode of the [Purdue Engineering Podcast].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Kong’s original intention was to study coal power plants during his undergraduate studies in China, yet after taking an “intro to nuclear energy” course, he learned of the importance of carbon-free emissions to the planet’s future. The nuclear industry’s reliability, emphasis on safety, and sustainability drew Dr. Kong to study nuclear engineering as a way to steer the world away from the toxicity of carbon emitters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Kong works at the Advanced Reactor Thermal-Hydraulics (ART) Laboratory at Purdue with the goal of design improvements for high-performing reactor systems. At ART, Kong has the capability to study fluid mechanics, heat and mass transfer, and safety in nuclear systems. His current focus is his work with the Versatile Test Reactor (VTR), a Department of Energy-funded program intended to accelerate and improve generation IV reactor designs. Dr. Kong is collaborating with Argonne National Laboratory and Idaho National Laboratory to design the VTR’s sodium-cooled cartridge loop to assist the development of sodium fast reactors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VTR program contributes directly to the United States’ ability to maintain its leadership in advanced reactor technologies, which was threatened by the shutdown of the Fast Flux Test Facility (FFTF) in the 1990s. The VTR re-establishes the testing capability, allowing for the continuous development of new materials and nuclear fuels for the next generation of reactors. The global market for nuclear power technology is estimated at $1 trillion, nuclear power generation is projected to grow 73% by 2040, and most of the existing reactors are on track to retire within the next few decades. Thus, the contributions of the VTR are crucial if the United States, and even the world, is to keep up with global energy demand in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of four episodes featuring Purdue University&amp;rsquo;s Nuclear Engineering. Listen to more about Nuclear Engineering and other engineering topics at the Purdue Engineering podcast website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Dix earns DOE Nuclear Energy University Program Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-neup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/dix-neup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Dix, an undergraduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University, has been awarded a Nuclear Energy University Program (NEUP) Fellowship from the the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE).The fellowship is awarded to students pursuing nuclear energy-related disciplines at universities across the country. Through this program the recipient will receive up to $50,000 a year over the next three years to help pay for their graduate studies and research, plus $5,000 toward a summer internship at a U.S. national laboratory or other approved facility to strengthen the ties between students and the Department’s nuclear energy research programs. The student will study a breadth of critical nuclear energy issues, from fuel cycle sustainability to reactor efficiency and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam will be receiving his bachelors in Nuclear Engineering from Purdue University May 2020. “Adam is excited to get his PhD at Purdue working on the Versatile Test Reactor, through the generous support of the DOE’ Integrated University Partnership program.” Adam’s future plans once he receives his PhD is to work at a national laboratory on liquid metal thermal-hydraulics and fast reactor safety, with an eye towards helping licenses and encouraging their widespread adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeremy Marquardt receives prestigious Rickover Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/marquardt-rickover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/marquardt-rickover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Marquardt, an undergraduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University and an undergraduate member of TRSL, has been awarded a Rickover Fellowship from the Naval Reactors Division of the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE). This opportunity is considered as one of the most prestigious fellowships in the nation, awarded to top students pursuing a Ph.D. degree in nuclear engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four-year fellowship is intended to provide education on the maintenance and development of science and engineering technology pertaining to naval nuclear propulsion and advancing fission energy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy is receiving his bachelors in Nuclear Engineering from Purdue in May 2020. After graduation he is planning to join Dr. Chatzidakis to develop a nuclear engineering research group at Purdue with a focus on AI and machine learning applications to nucelar reactor control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate student Zhengting Quan earns Purdue Ross Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/quan-ross/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/quan-ross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zhengting Quan, a graduate student at ART in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University, has been awarded a Ross Fellowship from the the University.The fellowship is awarded to incoming graduate students with recognized academic excellence. The Ross Fellowship includes funding for four years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ART Research at NURETH</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/nureth2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/nureth2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At NURETH 2019 in Portland, OR, several members of ART presented their work. Dr. Seungjin Kim presented a Keynote Lecture on geometric effects on two-phase flow, and Dr. Ran Kong presented research on relative motion between phases in horizontal two-phase flow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purdue NE will have a seat at the table of elite global gathering</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-oecd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Global Panel of Universities on Nuclear Energy Technology, Policy and Education, will commence July 24-25, 2019, in Paris, France, where 16 elite universities from NEA’s member countries are invited to attend. Purdue will be represented by Seungjin Kim, the Capt. James McCarthy Jr. and Cheryl E. McCarthy Head of the School of Nuclear Engineering, and Lefteri Tsoukalas, professor of Nuclear Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I saw the invitation letter, I was elated. This is a great honor,” said Kim. “Personally, I’m humbled and feel a great responsibility.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEA is an international organization consisting of 33 countries in Europe, the Americas, and the Asia-Pacific regions. Its mission is to provide safe, environmentally sound, and economical use of nuclear energy for peaceful purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its invitation letter, NEA explained that Purdue was chosen “because of your university’s record of excellence in nuclear engineering studies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a unique initiative in which the NEA will seek the advice and views of elite academic institutions to address the complex issues faced by global governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The world has entered a critical period that may determine the future of energy,” writes William D. Magwood, IV, the director-general of the OECD/NEA in his invitation letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is a growing recognition around the world that nuclear energy can play an important role in future, low-carbon energy systems, but also that long-term, creative thinking is needed to address today’s challenges.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have in-depth technical expertise and infrastructures, with which we can provide advice to the NEA to address all future issues of nuclear energy,” said Kim, referring to the invited universities. “We need to address climate change, how nuclear energy technology can be sustainable for the future of humanity, and how we can provide the world with a clean, safe and resilient energy source.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim said Purdue’s invitation makes perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Purdue Nuclear Engineering has been recognized for its nuclear power engineering and has been a leader from the get-go in the development of nuclear power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With its state-of-the-art research and educational infrastructures, Purdue is in a great position to provide a roadmap for the NEA and the rest of the countries in the world,” Kim said. “This invitation is yet another testimony that Purdue Engineering is at the Pinnacle of Excellence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purdue’s planned contributions to the Global Panel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the July meeting, all university participants were asked to present recommendations for items to be explored by the Global Panel of Universities on Nuclear Energy Technology, Policy and Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seungjin Kim, Lefteri Tsoukalas, and CoE Dean Mung Chiang collaborated and submitted the following discussion items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Capital Development: Educating Future Nuclear Engineers via Online Platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Analytics and Big Data, including Nuclear Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientific Facilities Sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclear as Sustainable Energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Seungjin Kim appointed to DOE Nuclear Energy Advisory Committee</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-doe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-doe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seungjin Kim, the Capt. James F. McCarthy, Jr. and Cheryl E. McCarthy Head of the School of Nuclear Engineering, has been appointed to the U.S. Department of Energy’s (DOE) Nuclear Energy Advisory Committee (NEAC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this new role, Kim will meet biannually with the 25 other committee members to advise the Secretary and the Assistant Secretary for Nuclear Energy on a number of issues. Items discussed include matters of national policy and scientific aspects of nuclear issues of concern to DOE, periodic reviews of the various program elements within DOE’s nuclear programs and recommendations based thereon, and the needs, views, and priorities of stakeholders of DOE’s nuclear programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am honored to be invited to assist the DOE’s Office of Nuclear Energy in shaping nation’s nuclear energy program,&amp;rdquo; Kim said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s an exciting time to be nuclear engineers with new opportunities for both existing and new nuclear applications, and I am thrilled to be part of DOE’s initiatives and being at the forefront in assisting these efforts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NEAC was established in 1998 and includes individuals from academia, industry, and national laboratories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the NEAC, visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.energy.gov/ne/services/nuclear-energy-advisory-committee&#34;&gt;https://www.energy.gov/ne/services/nuclear-energy-advisory-committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drew Ryan receives prestigious Rickover Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-rickover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/ryan-rickover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drew Ryan, an undergraduate student in the School of Nuclear Engineering at Purdue University, has been awarded a Rickover Fellowship from the Naval Reactors Division of the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE). This opportunity is considered as one of the most prestigious fellowships in the nation, awarded to top students pursuing a Ph.D. degree in nuclear engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four-year fellowship is intended to provide education on the maintenance and development of science and engineering technology pertaining to naval nuclear propulsion and advancing fission energy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his fellowship, Ryan will conduct research on reactor thermal hydraulics and two-phase flow. He will spend two summers at one of the Naval Nuclear Laboratories and work at one of the labs for two years after obtaining his Ph.D. in nuclear engineering at Purdue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to have this opportunity for my graduate work,” said Ryan. “The Naval Nuclear Labs are known for their high-quality work and their history of excellence, and I am grateful for the opportunity to work with them. I&amp;rsquo;m still a little in shock that I was chosen for this honor, but I think that I can do some amazing work with these labs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryan will be receiving his bachelors in Nuclear Engineering from Purdue University this month. During his undergraduate career, he completed research with Dr. Robert Bean in a variety of fields and also completed work on an advanced reactor safety analysis software at Argonne National Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seungjin Kim earns Highest ANS Recognition</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 15:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-fellow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seungjin Kim, the Capt. James F. McCarthy Jr. &amp;amp; Cheryl E. McCarthy Head of the School of Nuclear Engineering, has been elected to American Nuclear Society Fellow Grade, the highest membership grade of the ANS. The society has a membership of around 11,000 professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim will be among seven others to receive this elite honor during the Opening Plenary of the ANS Winter Meeting on Oct. 30 in Washington D.C. His framed certificate will read: “Dr. Kim has made contributions toward advancing reactor thermal-hydraulic analysis methods by developing dynamic two-phase flow models, developing advanced instrumentation that expanded capability of two-phase flow experiments, educating nuclear engineers in academics, and providing services to ANS through various leadership positions in the Thermal-Hydraulic Division and in professional meetings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim (MS ’92 EE, Ph.D ’99 NE) joined Purdue as head of NE in June 2017. He also holds a master’s degree in physics from South Dakota State University and a bachelor’s degree in physics from Sogang University, Seoul, Korea. He served as chair of the ANS Thermal Hydraulics Division (THD) in 2016-17 and previously as vice chair, secretary, and treasurer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim said he is humbled by the recognition. “This is the most important professional society for nuclear engineers in all areas of expertise,” he said, adding, “While I am delighted by this honor, I feel a greater responsibility as a member of the nuclear engineering community, as an educator and as a researcher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim also is a member of the American Society of Mechanical Engineering (ASME), Sigma Pi Sigma, Korea Nuclear Society (KNS), and Korean-American Scientist and Engineers Association (KSEA).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trustees approve professorships; honor retiring chancellor, donors</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 16:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/post/kim-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Purdue University Board of Trustees on Friday (Aug. 4) approved the appointment of six faculty to named and distinguished positions and approved resolutions of appreciation for the outgoing Fort Wayne campus chancellor and for significant donors to the university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seungjin Kim was named the Capt. James McCarthy, Jr., and Cheryl E. McCarthy Head of the School of Nuclear Engineering; Valerie S. Knopik was named the Ben and Maxine Miller Professor of Human Development and Family Studies; Julia Laskin was named the William F. and Patty J. Miller Professor of Chemistry; Jayson Lusk was named Distinguished Professor of Agricultural Economics; Donna M. Riley was named the Kamyar Haghighi Head of the School of Engineering Education; and Kipling D. Williams was named Distinguished Professor of Psychological Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim, who earned his master’s and doctoral degrees at Purdue, became head of the School of Nuclear Engineering on June 1. He came to Purdue from Pennsylvania State University. His research includes reactor thermal-hydraulics to reactor system analysis code and reactor safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
