<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spacer Grid | ART</title>
    <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/tags/spacer-grid/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/tags/spacer-grid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spacer Grid</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/img/thumbnail_bettis_churn.jpg</url>
      <title>Spacer Grid</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/tags/spacer-grid/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacer Grid Separate Effects</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-separate-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-separate-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The nuclear reactor coolant system is composed of various flow geometries and restrictions. Many geometric effects of two-phase flow encountered in a typical reactor system have not yet been fully examined, including the effect of rod bundle spacer grids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this research is to investigate the geometric effects of two- phase flow through a prototypic spacer grid to establish both the local and global database necessary for model development and code validation. The end goal is to develop predictive models that account for the effects of spacer grids and to serve as constitutive relations in the interfacial area transport equation. This model has been developed for various flow conditions and has been validated in an extensive database; however, further study on geometric effects is indispensable to establish a comprehensive and robust model. In view of this, the present test facility is designed to study the effects of rod bundle spacer grids on interfacial area transport in two-phase flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The facility employed is a scaled test facility based on a conventional pressurized water reactor. 19 dimensionless geometric parameters and five flow parameters were employed in the design of the facility to achieve similarity between the test facility and the prototypic system. The facility consists of a 1x3 array of 3.18 cm diameter simulant fuel rods with a pitch of 4.45 cm that are arranged in a rectangular channel with a 13.65 cm x 4.45 cm cross-section that spans 3.3 m from injection to outlet. The facility was designed as a narrow rectangular channel with clear acrylic sides and rods to facilitate flow visualization. Seven axial measurement locations are available along the length of the test section, one upstream of the spacer grid and six downstream of the spacer grid, to obtain measurements of local two-phase flow parameters throughout the channel cross-section&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-spacer-grid-separate-effects-two-phase-flow-test-facility&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-separate-effects/Figure1_hu4dbe404f0208bd5e32fda4625024808e_200742_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Spacer-grid separate-effects two-phase flow test facility&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-separate-effects/Figure1_hu4dbe404f0208bd5e32fda4625024808e_200742_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;444&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Spacer-grid separate-effects two-phase flow test facility
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A High speed camera is employed to perform flow visualizations to visually observe the effect of the spacer grid on flow regime transition. Four flow regimes are observed by researchers: Bubbly, Cap-Turbulent, Slug and Churn-Turbulent. Two major effects of the spacer grid on the flow regime transition are observed, bubble coalescence, and bubble breakup. The observation of larger bubbles after the spacer grid indicated bubble coalescence for various conditions. While during other conditions the increased quantity of smaller bubbles indicated bubble breakup occurring.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-spacer-grid-separate-effects-two-phase-flow-test-facility-schematic&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-separate-effects/Figure2_hu148efb9ca3a2c1c6f912540f74def933_89654_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Spacer-grid separate-effects two-phase flow test facility schematic.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-separate-effects/Figure2_hu148efb9ca3a2c1c6f912540f74def933_89654_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;66&#34; height=&#34;448&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Spacer-grid separate-effects two-phase flow test facility schematic.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacer Grid Thermal Hydraulics Program</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-th/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-th/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through the joint efforts of the Pennsylvania State University and the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission, an experimental Rod Bundle Heat Transfer (RBHT) facility was designed and built. The purpose of the facility is to collect fundamental rod bundle thermal-hydraulic data that can be used to develop and validate models for system codes used by the nuclear industry.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-test-facility-schematic&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-th/featured_hue6ac1dc8a4c9aa48e158e93ad0cccf50_353998_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Test facility schematic.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-th/featured_hue6ac1dc8a4c9aa48e158e93ad0cccf50_353998_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;390&#34; height=&#34;302&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Test facility schematic.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility is a once through electrically heated 7x7 rod bundle with prototypical PWR geometry. Spacer grids with mixing vanes are present and the instrumentation is specifically located such that the effect of the spacer grids on thermal-hydraulic phenomena such as pressure drop and heat transfer can be captured.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-bundle-cross-section-and-spacer-grid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-th/Figure2_hu4220c1c4a9dbaa7dea27d1830ff186ce_305718_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Bundle cross-section and spacer grid.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/spacer-grid-th/Figure2_hu4220c1c4a9dbaa7dea27d1830ff186ce_305718_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;511&#34; height=&#34;199&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Bundle cross-section and spacer grid.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To date, constant reflood, steam cooling, steam cooling with droplet injection and level swell experiments have been conducted under the supervision of the late Dr. Lawrence Hochreiter. Currently, the facility is being utilized under the Spacer Grid Thermal-Hydraulics (SGTH) program to study the effect of spacer grids under post CHF steady and oscillatory reflood conditions. Preliminary results show that for the same nominal reflood rate, oscillations in the flow decrease peak clad temperature but delay quench time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
