<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CFD | ART</title>
    <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/tags/cfd/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/tags/cfd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CFD</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/img/thumbnail_bettis_churn.jpg</url>
      <title>CFD</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/tags/cfd/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study and CFD Design Tool Development for the Cartridge Loop in the Versatile Test Reactor (VTR)</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/versatile-test-reactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/versatile-test-reactor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generation IV fast reactors operate at high temperature (500~1000°C) and fast neutron spectrum environment. In order to develop novel and advanced fuels and materials for advanced reactors, an intense fast neutron environment is needed for testing. However, no fast-reactor-based neutron source is available in U.S. since the shutdown of Fast Flux Test Facility (FFTF) in 1990s. As such, the Versatile Test Reactor (VTR) program is established to accelerate the testing and qualification of the new designs of fuel and materials. In VTR, an internal cartridge loop design with flowing different coolants (e.g., liquid metal, gas, and molten salt) is adopted to provide appropriate in-core environment. This design can isolate the test vehicle coolant loop from the primary reactor coolant to maximize the testing capability.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-schematic-of-the-vtr-cartridge-loop&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/versatile-test-reactor/featured_hue55cf0e9c218d7d7aeb7a34c9c6d24c3_34221_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;A schematic of the VTR cartridge loop&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/versatile-test-reactor/featured_hue55cf0e9c218d7d7aeb7a34c9c6d24c3_34221_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; height=&#34;504&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    A schematic of the VTR cartridge loop
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of the present research is to develop a CFD design tool for the cartridge loop in VTR. A scaling analysis is first performed to investigate the feasibility of using water loop to replace sodium loop, while CFD simulation is performed to support scaling analysis and/or to improve the test facility design. Heat transfer experiments will be performed on the constructed test facilities to investigate the overall functionality and performance of the cartridge loop at different boundary conditions. Test conditions may include steady-state parametric studies on flow rates and core power, and transient studies on increasing core power, loss of flow, etc. In the end, the CFD simulation results will be evaluated based on the obtained experimental data and a CFD design tool will be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Subcritical Testbed (HYST) Facility Design and Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/niowave-hyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/niowave-hyst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to develop novel and advanced fuels and materials for Generation IV reactors, an intense fast neutron environment is needed for testing.  Fast neutron fluxes greater than 1015 n/cm2s are required for radiation damage studies with significant displacements per atom (DPA), which are conventionally achieved with fast reactors.  However, since the shutdown of the Fast Flux Test Facility (FFTF), the United States (U.S.) has not had a fast-reactor-based neutron source.  To address this issue, Niowave, Inc. proposes to develop a HYbrid fast/thermal core configuration Subcritical Testbed (HYST) to provide a testing capability for novel designs of fuels and materials in a fast reactor like environment.  The fast core region of the testbed is cooled by liquid LBE and can provide a sufficient volume for testing advanced nuclear reactor materials in a liquid metal environment.  Considering that the proposed subcritical testbed facility is not a reactor, it will be cheaper and faster to license that a reactor.  In order for HYST to be realized, however, the thermal-hydraulic analysis of the designed systems needs to be performed using experimental data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current work, Purdue will assist Niowave, Inc. in test facility design and data analysis. This includes providing design considerations such as test loop components and setup, implementing various instruments and assisting Niowave, Inc. in developing plans for experiments such as test procedures, test conditions, and test plans.  In parallel, a CFD simulation on the test loop will be performed to investigate the hydrodynamics and heat transfer characteristics of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Diameter Horizontal Two-Phase Flow</title>
      <link>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/small-diameter-horizontal-two-phase-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/project/small-diameter-horizontal-two-phase-flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to develop and validate Multi-phase Computational Fluid Dynamics (MCFD) codes, an extensive database of two-phase flow information is required for various flow regimes, geometries, and orientations. Many two-phase flow experiments have been performed in vertical flow channel geometries, and thus a substantial number of databases exist to benchmark MCFD approaches in such conditions. However, there are few databases of local two-phase flow parameters acquired in straight horizontal flow channels available that are suitable for comparisons with MCFD and the development of multi-phase closure models. The present work establishes a horizontal, adiabatic, air-water, two-phase flow test facility to: (1) perform detailed flow visualizations, (2) study the interfacial structures and flow regime transitions, and (3) identify gas-phase interactions in air-water horizontal two-phase flow in relation to future interfacial area transport modeling efforts. Figures 1 and 2 highlight two of the bubble interaction mechanisms: turbulence impact breakup and random collision coalescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test facility is designed to be capable of performing experiments in a comprehensive range of horizontal two-phase flow conditions including bubbly, plug, slug, stratified, stratified-wavy, and annular flow regimes. The test section is desiged to provide an ideal condition for flow visualization and for the application of optical instrumentation. A high speed movie camera capable of capturing images at up to 32,000 frames per second is available and will be employed to perform flow visualization studies. In order to achieve a fully developed horizontal two-phase flow, clear acrylic pipes with 3.81 cm inner diameter are employed as the test section, which provide a total development length of more than 200 diameters.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-time-series-of-bubble-breakup-by-turbulence-impact-process-jf500-ms-jgatm005-ms-at-a-development-length-of-80-diameters&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/small-diameter-horizontal-two-phase-flow/featured_hue6ab6372ef8a3608623a2b2a9c59d865_33475_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Time series of bubble breakup by turbulence impact process. jf=5.00 m/s, jg,atm=0.05 m/s at a development length of 80 diameters.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/small-diameter-horizontal-two-phase-flow/featured_hue6ab6372ef8a3608623a2b2a9c59d865_33475_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;571&#34; height=&#34;410&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Time series of bubble breakup by turbulence impact process. jf=5.00 m/s, jg,atm=0.05 m/s at a development length of 80 diameters.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the first portion of this research is to perform a scoping experiment to study the effects of break angle and break length-to-diameter ratio (L/D) on the exchange rate during the postulated scenario. Here, water and brine are used as simulant fluids, and flow visualization and density measurement experiments have been performed. The exchange rate is expressed in terms of a non-dimensional Froude number which scales the inertia with respect to the buoyancy. The results obtained are compared with previous studies as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-time-series-of-bubble-coalescence-by-random-collision-process-jf500-ms-jgatm010-ms-at-a-development-length-of-80-diameters&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/small-diameter-horizontal-two-phase-flow/Figure2_hufba3f038738a404b83c23bf1d1cff9f9_31763_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Time series of bubble coalescence by random collision process. jf=5.00 m/s, jg,atm=0.10 m/s at a development length of 80 diameters.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/ARTH/ARTH/project/small-diameter-horizontal-two-phase-flow/Figure2_hufba3f038738a404b83c23bf1d1cff9f9_31763_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;574&#34; height=&#34;392&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
    Time series of bubble coalescence by random collision process. jf=5.00 m/s, jg,atm=0.10 m/s at a development length of 80 diameters.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
